[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to the channel
this is uh it's not one of our own
flavors i have seen this before
elsewhere
but we decided to recreate a duo tub now
i made this in the ice cream community
that we're part of if you want to join
this community links below
and everyone loved it so we're going to
show you how to do it it's
one half of the tub is coffee one half
of the tub is
donut flavored ice cream so if you want
to see how this is made
let's get stuck into it
so i'm going to show you how to make two
different versions of coffee ice cream
just very simply here
the first one is on the hob with coffee
beans themselves and for that just put
your milk and sugar in a pan
add 50 grams of your favorite ground
coffee beans
put them in and turn the heat off let it
sit there for half an hour
and then strain it through a cheesecloth
and pop that
in the fridge until you're ready to go
and the second coffee ice cream that
we're going to show you do is just using
instant coffee now for this one i just
took a little bit of the milk here
and put it in the microwave to warm it
up then added in the sugar and the
coffee granules themselves get it
nice and combined and add that warm mix
back to the cold milk to bring the
temperature down pop that in the fridge
again until we're ready to churn
[Music]
so for the donut ice cream i could only
get for some random reason
a mixed box of glazed donuts from krispy
kreme
thanks very much krispy kreme the dozen
original glazed have disappeared off the
face of the planet here
take whatever you can get and steep it
in the milk for 24 hours
in the fridge let that flavor soak in
well after 24 hours
strain it through and make sure you take
all the excess milk out of those donuts
you're going to be left with this
gelatinous
lump of dough at the end of it but um
just dispose of that you have no need
for that
you're going to need at least 400 ml
worth of milk for this recipe
so when you've got it strained pop it
back in the fridge until you're ready to
use it
[Music]
so the first one we're going to do is
the coffee ice cream take that milk
mix out of your fridge and add in your
cream get it fully incorporated
add in your milk powder and then put it
in your ice cream machine
to churn when it's ready
take it out and load it into one half of
your tub
leave it on its side cover the top with
a bit of cling film and put it in the
freezer for about half an hour until
your donut ice cream is finished
churning now whilst
the tub is in the freezer you're going
to churn your donut ice cream this is
the point where you put in your sugar
and your milk powder you
incorporate it well make sure the milk
powder is fully hydrated add in your
cream
and then turn it in your ice cream
machine now at that point you should be
about half an hour
since doing the coffee one take your tub
out the freezer take your cling film off
and fill in that void you might want to
stop your donut ice cream just a little
bit earlier than normal
just so you can get it right down into
the bottom of the tub make sure there's
no air pockets in there
when it's all full pop it back in the
freezer until you're ready to eat it
right the ice cream's been in the
freezer overnight we're gonna get some
out dish it up
see what it looks like
[Music]
great tub half and half like it clever
let's um let's scoop away
[Music]
there we go grape divide as you can see
i'll put the picture up just here but
you can see the two diff completely
different ice creams
so um let's see what they're like
[Music]
good strong coffee flavor on that one
so you can taste the donut now as i said
i only had four donuts in that whole box
of 12 there was only four original glaze
if you want to increase the flavor and
you can get a box of 12
then stick another couple of donuts in
there as well you can get artificial
donut flavour i don't know whether that
would work in this but
krispy kreme doughnuts i mean they're
not loaded in flavor let's be honest
they're okay
we're a bit limited in the uk is what we
can get but i know in us you get
loads and loads of different flavors and
some much better donuts than krispy
kreme
but this is a really great combo i mean
donuts and coffee who doesn't love that
combo
the two different ways of doing the
coffee ice cream is completely up to you
if you're an instant coffee drinker just
use that if that's your favorite flavor
if you're a
bean aficionado take your favorite roast
grind it up and put it in there you
don't need to leave the beans to soak
for days and days
after 30 minutes in the warm milk it'll
be done all the flavor will be out
you'll be good to go
nice i say it's simple it is relatively
simple duo tubs you can do this for any
combination you like but
i hope you enjoyed this one next video
is going to be
a dairy-free one ben and jerry's
recreation using
one of their sunflower ice cream ranges
so hope you stick around for that one
for now thanks for watching don't forget
to like and subscribe and we'll see you
on the next one